Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm 5918 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes 1938-1939 (Reel 8)
  - 0500. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 14, 1939. 420 pages., 4 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Actors jurisdiction extension; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress appeal for assistance; Oregon anti-labor law; National Youth Administration apprentice training; Associated Farmers anti-labor activities; Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; boycott of German-made goods; Building Service Employees dispute and agreement with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; Congress of Industrial Organizations dissociated from Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Carpenters Union jurisdiction disputes; Congress of Industrial Organizations-American Federation of Labor peace negotiations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in Butte, Montana; Dies Committee; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee; National Labor Relations Board appointments; Labor's Non-Partisan League; National Labor Relations Act amendments; refugee legislation; wages and hours act (Walsh-Healey Fair Labor Standards Act); seniority rights of African American railroad maids; African American voting rights in the south; African American membership in American Federation of Labor; Longshoremen dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; labor relations in Mexico; Progressive Mine Workers of America; National Youth Administration and national defense; neon sign industry jurisdiction; Pan American Federation of Labor; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction expansion; Seafarers International Union report; State, County, and Municipal Employees jurisdiction; Teamsters dispute with Brewery Workers in Detroit; Textile Workers of America re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Fort Wayne, Indiana, Housing Plan.
  - 0920. Meeting Minutes of March 22-23, 1939. 45 pages., 5 (Reel 8)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations pace negotiations; Associated Farmers; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers; United Mine Workers; Oil Field, Gas Well, and Refinery Workers; Western Federation of Miners; Textile Workers of America; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Automobile Workers.
- Minutes 1939-1940 (Reel 9)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of May 10-19, 1939. 180 pages., 1 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Actors jurisdiction extension; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Automobile Workers jurisdiction; Balfour Declaration on Palestine; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Operating Engineers jurisdiction matters; Laborers jurisdiction dispute with Operating Engineers; Longshoremen's Dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; American Federation of Labor Maritime Department proposed; Progressive Miners Union of America; Street and Electric Railway Employees dispute with Teamsters over Bus Operators organizing; American Federation of Labor organizing report; Pan American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0181. Meeting Minutes of August 7-18, 1939. 258 pages., 2 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: American Actors and Artists of America jurisdiction dispute with American Federation of Actors and Theatrical Stage Employees; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress dissociation from Congress of Industrial Organizations; Carpenters jurisdiction disputes; Japanese aggression in China; American Federation of Labor legislative program; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Molders Union dispute with Stove Mounters Union and Foundry Workers Union; discrimination against African Americans by American Federation of Labor unions; Upholsterers dispute with Carpenters; women's auxiliaries representation in State Federations of Labor; prevailing wages in Works Progress Administration work; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Summary of Legal Activities of American Federation of Labor.
  - 0439. Meeting Minutes of October 1, 9, and 14-15, 1939. 96 pages., 3 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Injunction case in New Orleans; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Carpenters jurisdiction dispute with Machinists over Millwrights; resolution for judicial recall; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; discrimination against African American workers by American Federation of Labor unions; National Labor Relations Act amendments; Oregon anti-labor law; Upholsterers agreement with Painters disapproved; Textile Workers organizing campaign; Upholsterers dispute with Carpenters; federal labor unions for warehousemen; Works Progress Administration working condition; Works Progress Administration Minneapolis strike and prevailing wage controversy; anti-Communist resolutions.
  - 0535. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 9, 1940. 206 pages., 4 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Oregon antilabor law; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Service Employees jurisdiction expansion; United States Department of Justice indictments of Building Trades unions for antitrust violations; Painters Union agreement with Stove Mounters; proposed federal health security legislation; Conference on War Mobilization of Industry; United States Housing Authority; National Labor Relations Act amendments; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; indictments of striking Works Progress Administration workers in Minneapolis; Newspaper Guild in Chicago; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Westbrook Pegler attacks on American Federation of Labor leaders; picketing rights; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction expansion; American Federation of Labor Committee on Taxation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0741. Meeting Minutes of May 13-21, 1940. 162 pages., 5 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor building; American Federationist business; British Trades Union Congress; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; Circus, Carnival, Fairs, and Rodeo International Union charter application and request for assistance; Immigration Service transfer from Labor to Justice Department; American Federation of Labor planks to political parties conventions; injunction relief legislation and antitrust relief legislation; housing; immigration; Ladies Garment Workers reaffiliation with American Federation of Labor; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Machinists jurisdiction disputes; war mobilization of industry; Tobacco Workers International Union internal controversy; Virginia State Federation of Labor; indictments of Minneapolis Works Progress Administration Strikers; finances and membership statistics.
  - 0903. Meeting Minutes of September 30-October 10, 1940. 122 pages., 6 (Reel 9)
    Major Topics: Theatrical Agents and Managers Union jurisdiction extension; Southern Tenant Farmers Union charter application; Building and Construction Trades Department disputes with Machinists; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; Brotherhood of Railway Clerks jurisdiction matters; conscription exemption from union taxes; Congress of Industrial Organizations-American Federation of Labor peace negotiations; Workers Education Bureau; social security; American Federation of Labor opposition to appointment of Sidney Hillman to National Defense Commission; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; National Labor Relations Act amendments; nonpartisan political policies; presidential campaign; American Federation of Labor policies on suspension of international unions; Virginia State Federation of Labor.
- Minutes 1940-1942 (Reel 10)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of September 30-October 10, 1940 (continued). 84 pages., 1 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department disputes with State, County, and Municipal Employees; postwar economic planning; workers education; application of antitrust to labor unions; American Federation of Labor organizing drives; American Federation of Labor policies on suspension of international unions; proposed American Federation of Labor libel suit against Westbrook Pegler; labor racketeering; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0085. Meeting Minutes of November 17-29, 1940. 28 pages., 2 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legal fees; American Federation of Labor policies on suspension of international unions; Stove Mounters and Molders protests.
  - 0113. Meeting Minutes of February 10-20, 1941. 202 pages., 3 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Alien migration to the United States; Oregon anti- labor law; protest application of antitrust law to labor unions by Thurman Arnold; Automobile Workers organizing; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; opposition to youth replacement of adult Civilian Conservation Corps workers; American Federation of Labor anti-Communist resolution; collective bargaining in national defense industries; Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; Operating Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters; Grain Processors application for charter application; antistrike and compulsory arbitration legislation; compulsory work legislation; Longshoremen settlement with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Montgomery Ward unfair labor practices case; racketeering charges in Painters Union; Pan American Federation of Labor rehabilitation; Pegler libel suit; Sleeping Car Porters legislation regarding conductors; shipbuilding industry; wage rates in defense construction; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0315. Meeting Minutes of May 19-28, 1941. 159 pages., 4 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Variety Actors Betterment committee and American Federation of Actors; American Federation of Labor opposition to antistrike legislation; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Conductors; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; Ice Pullers jurisdiction dispute among Teamsters, Operating Engineers and Firemen, and Oilers; Kohler Company strike; Machinists strike at San Francisco shipyards; racketeering in Painters Union; American Federation of Labor per capita taxes; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0474. Meeting Minutes of August 4-13, 1941. 107 pages., 5 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing conflict with Machinists at Allis Chalmers Company; Boiler Makers agreement with Plumbers; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; anti-labor legislation; Communist activity in American Federation of Teachers; housing; application of antitrust law to unions; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; postwar reconstruction; labor standards in public contracts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0581. Meeting Minutes of October 5, 14, and 17, 1941. 36 pages., 6 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Alaskan defense workers; anti-labor legislation; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; embargo of Japan; migrant labor; investigation of Minneapolis Central Labor Union; National Labor Relations Board.
  - 0617. Meeting Minutes of December 16 and 18, 1941. 21 pages., 7 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation, Smith Bill; President's Conference of Employers and Employees in War Production Industries.
  - 0638. Meeting Minutes of January 12-17, 1942. 130 pages., 8 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; anti-labor legislation; Civilian Conservation Corps merger with National Youth Association; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; American Federation of Labor purchase of Defense Bonds; Distillery Workers dispute with Seagram Company; Machinists dispute with Building Trades Department and Carpenters over Tennessee Valley Authority; office employees unions organization; price controls; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; War Labor Board established.
  - 0768. Meeting Minutes of May 13-22, 1942. 141 pages., 9 (Reel 10)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Anglo-Soviet-American Trade Union committee proposed; Boys Town, Nebraska; William H. Davis, chair of War Labor Board, anti-union attitude; Engineers dispute with Machinists and Building Trades Department; application of antitrust to labor unions; anti-labor legislation; charges of bias against National Labor Relations Board; Pan American Labor Conference; prison labor in war production; wage stabilization; War Bond salary deduction.
- Minutes 1942-1944 (Reel 11)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of May 13-22, 1942 (continued). 36 pages., 1 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Special Report on American Federation of Labor; Present Financial Status.
  - 0037. Meeting Minutes of August 4-13, 1942. 143 pages., 2 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; arbitration; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; collective bargaining in defense industries; labor relations in United States Navy; anti-labor legislation; antiracketeering legislation; Dies Committee; housing; application of anti-trust to labor unions; maritime labor legislation; Nationality Act; War Manpower Commission; subversive activities; women and children in war production; War Production Board; strikes, communication from Under Secretary of War Robert Patterson; wartime wage policies; war prisoners relief; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0180. Meeting Minutes of October 4-6 and 15, 1942. 47 pages., 3 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee, inclusion of Congress of Industrial Organizations and Railroad Brotherhoods; anti-labor legislation in California, "Hot Cargo" legislation; Machinists disputes with Carpenters and Buildings and Construction Department; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People telegram to American Federation of Labor regarding African American workers; Anglo-Soviet Trades Union Council; collective bargaining in war industries; housing for war workers; immigration; anti-trust; maritime legislation; National War Labor Board; wages and benefits of government employees; Executive Order on overtime pay.
  - 0227. Meeting Minutes of January 18-27, 1943. 200 pages., 4 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Absenteeism in war industries; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; American Federation of Labor representation on government boards and committees in war production; Anglo-American-Soviet trade Union Association; Anglo-American trade Union Committee; anti-labor legislation; anti-closed shop litigation in Florida; housing for war workers; inter-American affairs; Kaiser Shipbuilding case; Los Angeles Central Labor Council; Pan American Federation of Labor; wage and price stabilization; Works Progress Administration liquidated; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0427. Meeting Minutes of May 17-22, 1943. 141 pages., 5 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters over aircraft plants; anti-labor legislation, Smith-Connally bill, anti-trust; Kaiser shipyards case; investigation of Los Angeles Central Labor Council; United Mine Workers application for re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; National Labor Relations Board ad Kaiser shipyard case; National War Labor Board; no-strike pledge; Oil Refinery Workers jurisdiction; report on American Federation of Labor legal Cases; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0568. Meeting Minutes of August 9-16, 1943. 135 pages., 6 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; proposed repeal of Chinese Exclusion Act; cigarettes for servicemen campaign; European relief, aid to underground movements; American Federation of Labor legal report; anti-trust; Machinists withdrawal from American Federation of Labor; National Labor Relations Board; National War Labor Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; price controls and rationing; United Mine Workers re-affiliation; United Nations Relief Committee; American Legion Labor Posts; prisoners of war used for war labor; Connally-Smith Act threat to no-strike pledge; American Federation of Labor political activities; Progressive Miners of America re-affiliation with United Mine Workers; Women's Trade Union League; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0703. Meeting Minutes of October 3, 5-6, 13, and 15, 1943. 48 pages., 7 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Brotherhood of Railway Car Men jurisdiction; Los Angeles Central Labor Union; Machinists reinstatement in American Federation of Labor; United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor.
  - 0751. Meeting Minutes of January 17-27, 1944. 236 pages., 8 (Reel 11)
    Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation in general and in Florida; Chemical Workers charter application; book on closed shop; centralization of United States Department of Labor; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee Report; Bernardo Ibanez, Chilean Labor delegation; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Labor Office; Progressive Mine Workers of America protest United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; National Labor Relations Board amendment to authority; American Federation of Labor opposition to National Service Act; National War Labor Board powers protested; American Federation of Labor legal actions report; American Federation of Labor political activity; prisoners of war labor; postwar economic planning; Paul Robeson membership in Congress of Industrial Organizations; Eleanor Roosevelt; soldiers voting rights legislation; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
- Minutes 1944-1945 (Reel 12)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of January 17-27, 1944 (continued). 34 pages., 1 (Reel 12)
    Major Topic: International Council of Office Employees Unions.
  - 0035. Meeting Minutes of May 1-9, 1944. 179 pages., 2 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations political collaboration disapproved; anti-labor legislation; Brotherhood of Railway Clerks jurisdiction matters; Operating Engineers bargaining agency in oil refineries and jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; George-Murray bill on war contracts; America Federation of Labor Housing Committee; immigration and nationalization of Indians; labor conscription; United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; Montgomery Ward labor dispute; National War Labor Board; discrimination against African American workers; American Federation of Labor political platforms sent to major parties; Railway Clerks controversy with Railroad Telegraphers; Philadelphia Transportation Workers; Conference of Office Employees Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0214. Meeting Minutes of August 21-29, 1944. 111 pages., 3 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: British Trades Union Congress; Chemical Workers charter application; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; American Federation of Labor litigation; Fair Labor Standards Act; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers controversy; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee; American Federation of Labor representative visit to Italy; Office Employees charter application; American Federation of Labor litigation against anti-labor laws; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0325. Meeting Minutes of November 19, 22, 28, and December 1, 1944. 46 pages., 4 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: British Trades Union Congress; National War Labor Board; Confederation of Workers of Latin America; Machinists dispute with Operating Engineers; United Mine Workers re-affiliation; World Trade Union Conference.
  - 0371. Meeting Minutes of February 5-15, 1945. 171 pages., 5 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Anti-labor laws in Florida; Cannery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters over warehousemen; Central Labor Unions as collective bargaining agencies; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace initiative; Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor organizing; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; Federal Labor Unions; International Federation of trade Unions; discrimination against Japanese Americans; American Federation of Labor litigation; federal aid to education bill; work-or-fight bill; universal military training; Progressive Mine Workers of America protest re-affiliation of United Mine Workers; United Nations San Francisco convention; veterans aid; white-only democratic primary elections; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0542. Meeting Minutes of April 30-May 8, 1945. 164 pages., 6 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations in Canada; Aluminum Workers charter application; World trade Union Conference; Code of Principles for Labor and Management by American Federation of Labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; and Chamber of Commerce; Congress of Industrial Organizations influence on postwar planning; Grain Processors charter application; American Federation of Labor meeting with farmers' organizations; amendments to National Labor Relations Act suggested by Metal Trades Department; African Americans relationship to American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor organizing policies; Theatrical Stage Employees dispute with Painters; postwar reconversion program; Executive Council meeting with President Truman; United Nations Conference in San Francisco; American Federation of Labor proposed amendments to Dumbarton Oaks Proposals; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0706. Meeting Minutes of August 6-14, 1945. 175 pages., 7 (Reel 12)
    Major Topics: Associated Actors and Artist; Code of Principles of American Federation of Labor, United States Chamber of Commerce, and Congress of Industrial Organizations; Aluminum Workers charter application; veterans seniority issues; Building Trades Department disputes with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; Canadian Seamen's Union; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Car Men, Railway, and Shop Crafts Brotherhoods; strike and jurisdiction controversy among Hollywood studio unions; Communist activity in southern California; Federal Industrial Relations Act; Hod Carriers dispute with Building Trades Department; American Federation of Labor litigation against state anti-labor legislation; amendments to National Labor Relations Act; organizing of women in industry; National Labor Relations Board; no-strike pledge discontinued; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0881. Meeting Minutes of October 15-124, 1945. 100 pages., 8 (Reel 12)